Hello and thank you for selecting this course.
The complete NFC Contactless Smart Cards course, which is the only course you need to learn about these
technologies.
The goal here is to teach you everything you need to become an RF expert.
I guess I should introduce myself first.
So I'm basically an electronics engineer, and since 2014 I started working as an RFID engineer.
And then, believe it or not, I actually have interests outside of that, including but not limited
to running, swimming, traveling, playing guitar, and photography.
In fact, I decided to create this training to share with you my knowledge in this field and present
to you in detail all the characteristics linked to RFID in general and to the NFC field in particular.
For more than ten years, I have had the pleasure of traveling all over the world and training students,
engineers, and developers in RFID and NFC technologies.
As noted in the description, this course is for all levels, from beginners to RF experts.
This is a course for electronics and IT students, system integrators, software developers, and RF
engineers and technicians who create smart card computer application or who also develop antennas,
chips, readers, or applications that communicate with contactless cards, RFID labels, and RFID tags.
This training aims to give the reader the basic skills necessary to design and implement a solution
involving a contactless smart card.
It contains a large part related to NFC technology communication between contactless reader and cards,
RLC circuits, antenna design, etc., etc..
As it's a subject that we do not study at school and very limited in documentation, I decided to share
with you my knowledge as an RF engineer that I acquired during ten years of experience.
So let's start.
Here are the different topics that we will discuss through this training.
So as you noticed, the first section will be an introduction to present what we will learn during this
training.
Through the second section, I will present the RFID system.
In general, there will be two presentation of the RFID technology.
The first one will be a basic presentation and the second will be a very advanced presentation.
During these two presentations, I will be answering the following questions.
What's the meaning of RFID?
What is an RFID system?
How does RFID work?
What are the RFID applications?
What are the RFID frequency range?
What are the differences between active and passive RFID systems?
What does an RFID system contain?
Which is a very common question from my students.
Same thing for what does an RFID reader contain?
And finally, what's the principle of inductive coupling?
Then through the third section we will talk more specifically about the NFC technology.
During this section, I will be answering the following question.
What's the meaning of NFC?
What's the NFC technology?
What are the NFC methods?
How does the physical operation in high frequency work?
What are the different high frequency standards?
As you may know here we will be talking about the ISO standard.
It's a very important part.
It's a very important topic which defines the communication between a reader and a card, between a
PCD and a pic.
We will talk about that later.
And what is the relationship between NFC and security?
After that, I will present in detail all the different actors and aspects of the communication between
a reader and a smart card.
And here are the questions that I will be answering during this section.
So what's a smart card?
What are the different types of smart cards?
What's the pick and what it's made of?
What's the PCD and what it's made of?
Here when I say pick, I'm talking about the card.
And when I say PCD, I'm talking about the reader.
Then how do I pick and the PCD communicate.
What are the different modes of communication?
What are the standards for proximity cards and what are the possible applications?
Then in the following sections, we will be presenting the different analog and digital aspects and
characteristics of the communication between a reader and the card.
And here are the topics that I will go through regarding the analog aspects.
I will present the physical characteristics of the communication, the different antenna sizes, the
pick antenna classes, the alternating magnetic field test, RMF, RF power and signal interface, the
operating field strength of the communication.
How is the pack powered by the RF field?
When I say our field, I mean the field generated by the PCD by the reader.
What frequency range is supported?
How do a PCD and the PC communicate?
Here.
We are still talking about the analog aspects.
What are the card types?
We know that we have two types type A and type B.
What is the difference between type A and type B?
What are the board rates?
I mean, what are the bit rates or the speeds of communication supported and what are the different
types of modulation?
What about the digital aspects of the communication?
I will present the different the following topics.
Initialization and county collision.
Definition of the different commands and answers.
What are the layer three commands?
What are the different spaces States machine what are the transmission protocols?
How to detect and communicate with one pack among several packs.
How to initialize the communication between a PCD and the selected pack.
And then I will present some examples of exchanges for a type A card and the type B card from the beginning
to the end.
And finally.
We will reach the last topic, the last section, which will be the antenna design for cards.
To be honest, I didn't at the beginning.
I didn't think about including this topic.
But then I still thought it's related to what we will learn through the the sections before.
So for antenna design for cards, I will.
I will answer the following question.
What are the basic RF parameters of high frequency cards?
What is the phenomenon of resonance in electronics?
What is the global approach to antenna design?
What are the steps from the technical requirement to the final product?
And what tests should be carried out to validate the best antenna solution?
As you may know, all the sections will be divided into sections to organize and differentiate and differentiate
the the the different topics.
I hope that everything is clear to you.
By the way, by the end of each session, there will be a conclusion or a quiz to make sure that you
understand everything and get the most important information.
So let's continue.